Tiffany R. Ragsdale

417-466-0642 | TiffanyRRagsdale@gmail.com | Columbia, MO

Copywriter • Copy Editor • Inbound Marketing Consultant • Content Creator • Content Editor

Profile

Experienced freelance writer specializing in both copy and content production as well as editing. Working with B2B and B2C companies to develop, create, and publish content and copy that serves to organically grow their customer base while increasing their current retention rate. Certified inbound marketing consultant working with businesses to implement the associated methodology. Such services include targeted keyword research, content ideation, social media and editorial calendar creation, and email marketing outlines.

Delve further into my skills, experience, and focus areas by visiting my digital portfolio.

Skills

- Content Creation
 Copywriting
 Search Engine Optimization
 CRM (Salesforce)
- Content Marketing Strategy
 Social Media Marketing
 CMS (Wordpress)
 CSS
- Graphic Design
 Copy Editing
 Targeted Keyword Research
 Copy Editing
 HTML

Education

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature & New Media

Marylhurst University, 2015, 3.9 GPA

Inbound Marketing Certification

HubSpot, 2016

Content Marketing Certification

HubSpot, 2017

Experience

Copy Editor Jan. 2018 - Current

• Editing branded copy to ensure it flows smoothly as well as grabs the attention of the audience.

Heartland Dental (Contract via Creative Circle: January 2018 - May 2018)

- Assisted web admins with new client website setups using their in-house CMS.
- Uploaded copy to newly created websites.
- Edited copy to ensure both grammatical and content accuracy as well as consistency.
- Heavy focus on SEO best practices during copy editing procedures to boost each client's organic search rankings upon publication.

Copywriter & Content Creator

Aug. 2015 - Current

- Writes, researches, and edits copy and content for B2B and B2C companies in various types of categories and formats, including social media posts, blog posts, landing pages, and product descriptions.
- Using search engine optimization to increase the client's search engine ranking organically.
- Follows AP Style or client's guidelines when writing and editing articles.
- Matches the language and tone of copy and content to each brand's voice.
- Creates social media copy for a range of platforms, including Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Google+.

LocalVox (Vivial)

Jan. 2017 - Current

• Writes SEO-heavy copy and content focused on building brand awareness and expanding customer base at the local or regional level for clients across the U.S.

- Completes three to six article requests 300 to 500 words each per day, totaling around 60 to 120 pieces per month.
- Creates month-long social media calendars for eight to 16 clients per month, which includes crafting copy and selecting media for outlined campaigns.

ContentWriters, LLC Nov. 2016 - Current

- Working with national and global clients across a range of industries, including rideshare, travel, and transportation.
- Primarily focused on educational content articles for repeat clients, ranging from 500 to 1,000 words.
- Occasional copy creation focused on branding or specific product promotion, such as product descriptions.

Inbound Marketing Consultant

Aug. 2016 - Current

Assisting companies with the implementation of the inbound marketing methodology.

Sherpa (Contract via Creative Circle: January 2017 - February 2017)

- Created buyer persona graphics for the B2B SaaS company's sales team based on their current customers and leads, including the complete buyer's journey and buying cycle.
- Completed in-depth targeted keyword research based on their buyer personas.
- Provided detailed content ideation suggestions based on the results of the keyword research.
- Created a content editorial calendar and social media calendar specific to the needs of the company with each spanning 12 months.
- Developed comprehensive guides for the Director of Communications covering search engine optimization, social media marketing, and email marketing based on the current and future needs of the company.
- Completed website audit and reviewed social media platforms to provide suggestions based on SEO and copy best practices.

Specialties

- Marketing
 Dental
 Real Estate
 Finance
 B2B
 SaaS
 Construction
 HVAC
 Travel
- Plumbing
 Legal
 Pro AV & Cinema Screens
 On-Demand Industries

Notable Clients

- Strong | MDI B2B Pro AV & Cinema Screen Manufacturer (via ContentWriters LLC)
- BusTickets.com B2C Regional & National Bus Ticket Booking Service (via ContentWriters LLC)
- Heartland Dental B2B Non-Clinical Support Services for Dental Practices (via Creative Circle)
- Sherpa B2B CRM Software Company Specializing in the Senior Housing Industry (via Creative Circle)
- <u>Rideshare Central</u> B2C Knowledge-Based Company Specializing in the On-Demand Sector (via ContentWriters LLC)
- <u>Time Shred</u> B2B & B2C Regional Professional Shredding Company Providing Commercial & Regional Document Destruction (via ContentWriters LLC)
- <u>Beach.com</u> B2C Hotel & Beach Resorts Specialist Offering Guidance With Customer Destination Selection (via ContentWriters LLC)